American Warships is a action, thriller, science
fiction film directed by Thunder Levin.
When an alien force wages war on Earth, only the crew of the USS Iowa
- the last American battleship, stands in their way.
Captain Winston, played by Mario Van Peebles.
General McKraken, played by Carl Weathers.
Lt. Caroline Bradley, played by Johanna Watts.
Dr. Julia Flynn, played by Nikki McCauley.
Lt. Cmdr. Juarez, played by Devin McGee.
Lookout Dunbar, played by Mandela Van Peebles.
American Warships is a 2012 science fiction war film directed
by Thunder Levin and distributed by The Asylum.
It premiered on the Syfy Channel on May 15, 2012.
In the tradition of The Asylum's film catalog, the film is an extremely low-budget
mockbuster of the Hasbro Studios/Universal Pictures film Battleship.
Initially, the film was titled American Battleship, but Universal later involved The Asylum
in a copyright lawsuit over the film due to its resemblance to their film.
As a result of the controversy, the film's name
was changed to American Warships.
The tone is thought_provoking and intense.